Andres Escala

Full Stack Developer



Personal Info

Email

andres.escala@hotmail.com andres.escala.344@gmail.com

Phone

+52 5545464585

Skills

HTML5, CSS3 y
Javascript

Nodejs, EJS, Reactjs

Git and Github
Management

MySQL, SQL Server
and MongoDB
databases

Linux - Ubuntu and CentOS 7

WebApps deployment on Netlify, GitHub Pages, and Azure

C#, .Net and ASP .Net Framework





Software

Microsoft Office $\star\star\star\star\star$

Languages

English: B2

Spanish: native

Full Stack developer and 10th semester telematics engineering student with +2 years experience in web applications and RESTFULL API development in .NET (+2 year), Node.js and Express.js (+2 years); 1 year experience on Frontend Apps dev with React.js. One year experience in managing SQL Server and MongoDB databases.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/escalandres/ GitHub repository: https://github.com/escalandres Portfolio: https://escalandres-portfolio.vercel.app/

Work History

2024-08

GenO Intern

- present

Oracle, Mexico City

- · Technical Consultant on NetSuite
- Generate innovation projects
- · Assist in technical projects

2022-11 - 2024-08

Web Developer Intern

Info100 S.A de C.V, Mexico City

- Development of web apps with ASP.NET Framework 4.6, .NET Core 6 and 8, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax and Bootstrap.
- Maintenance of desktop apps with .NET Framework 4.6 and Visual Basic.
- · Management of CentOS 7 linux servers.
- · Backend development using .NET and SQL Server.

2022-08

Internship Student

- 2022-10

New Ventures, Mexico City

- · Development of an administration system in ClickUp.
- Development of a landing page with HTML5, CSS3 and WordPress

Education

2020-01

Telematics, Bachelor of Telematics Engineering

- present

Instituto Politecnico Nacional, Mexico City

Projects

2022-11

Web developer

- present

PLD_WEB

Web application for preventing money laundering in microfinance companies; developed with ASP.NET Framework, Bootstrap 4 and SQL Server

2023-12

Web developer

- present

CONDUSEF Management

Web application to facilitate the uploading of complaints reports and clarifications from for the financial institution the CONDUSEF entity

2023-07

MyYT_Downloader

- 2023-08

A youtube videos downloader desktop app developed with Node.js, Express.js Electron.js, HTML5, CSS3 and Bootstrap 5. Available: https://github.com/escalandres/myyt-downloader

Certificates

2022-02

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals